http://www.austinwomenshealth.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to Main Content
Privacy Policy
Austin Women’s Health Center respects and is committed to protecting the privacy of users of our websites, applications, and other online services (collectively, the “Online Services”). We want our Online Services to be safe and helpful, and to help make you aware of our data practices we drafted this Privacy Policy, which describes the ways in which Austin Women’s Health Center uses, discloses, and collects information from or about you through www.austinwomenhealth.com and all other Online Services that link to this policy. Please be aware that your use of the Online Services is not guaranteed to be anonymous, and Austin Women’s Health Center may collect, use, and disclose information about your use of the Online Services as set forth in this Privacy Policy.
Important note: This Privacy Policy does not apply to information you may share with Austin Women’s Health Center in connection with your receipt of healthcare services online or via in-person visits at Austin Women’s Health Center. Such information is protected by state and federal law.
FULL PRIVACY POLICY
This Privacy Policy describes the ways in which Austin Women’s Health Center uses, discloses, and collects information from or about you through the Online Services. By using the Online Services, you consent to the processing of your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy, now and as amended by us.
How do we use your information?
We and our affiliates may use the information we collect from or about you through the Online Services for a number of purposes, including, but not limited to:
providing you with products, services, or information you request;
processing any transactions you have authorized;
following up on services or information we provided to you;
contacting you about fundraising campaigns or advocacy efforts;
delivering advertisements targeted to your interests based on your previous activity on the Online Services (commonly referred to as “Targeted Advertisements”) as well as other marketing communications, promotional materials, or advertisements that may be of interest to you;
conducting research;
promoting Austin Women’s Health Center’s services or illustrating the importance of reproductive health and rights;
processing an employment, internship, or volunteer application;
providing you with information about the Online Services or required notices;
allowing us to improve the Online Services and the services we provide, such as by better tailoring our content to our users’ needs and preferences;
generating and analyzing statistics about your use of the Online Services; and
detecting, preventing, and responding to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our Terms of Use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Online Services.
We also may combine or aggregate any of the information we collect through the Online Services or elsewhere for any of these purposes, including for the delivery of Targeted Advertisements.
To further demonstrate how we and our affiliates may use the information we collect from or about you through the Online Services, we provide the following examples:
If you make a donation via the Online Services, your information will be added to one or more of our supporter lists and databases, and you may be contacted about other Austin Women’s Health Center activities, news, and/or fundraising campaigns.
If you join or opt-in to our activist network, you will receive informational updates and action alerts about reproductive health and rights issues. In addition, your information will be added to one or more of our supporter lists and databases, and you may be contacted about other Austin Women’s Health Center activities, news, and/or fundraising campaigns.
If you view certain content on the Online Services, we or a service provider of ours may later display an advertisement related to that content on a different webpage that you visit through the Online Services or on another non-Austin Women’s Health Center website that has a relationship with the service provider.
If you use our website to submit your resume or materials for a paid or volunteer position, your information will be stored in a centralized database and may be accessible to our separately incorporated affiliates, who may be seeking candidates for full-time, part-time, or volunteer positions.
Under what circumstances do we disclose your information?
We may disclose the information we collect from or about you through the Online Services:
to our affiliates;
to service providers who work on our behalf and who have agreed to keep the information confidential and use the information solely to carry out the services that they are performing for us, including, but not limited to, service providers who process credit card transactions, facilitate our fundraising activities and campaigns, and deliver Targeted Advertisements on our behalf;
to other organizations that work with us for the provision of co-branded communications about Austin Women’s Health Center and those organizations’ products or services;
to other organizations with whom Austin Women’s Health Center participates in exchanges of donor information (e.g., donor list rental) and the service providers that facilitate such exchanges;
as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, a court order, or government reporting obligations;
when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary (a) to protect our rights, the integrity of the Online Services, or your safety or the safety of others, or (b) to detect, prevent, or respond to fraud, intellectual property infringement, violations of our Terms of Use, violations of law, or other misuse of the Online Services; and
to service providers, advisors, and other third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to proceed with the negotiation or completion of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets.
In addition, we may share de-identified information, such as reports on user demographics and traffic patterns, with third parties, including researchers.
The Online Services also may contain links to third-party websites and applications for your convenience and information. Austin Women’s Health Center does not control those third-party websites and applications or their privacy practices, which may differ from ours, and we do not endorse or make any representations about those third-party websites and applications. You acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the collection and use of your information by third-party websites and applications that are not under our control, and such information is not governed by this Privacy Policy. Remember that we cannot protect your privacy once you leave the Online Services, so when you visit third-party websites and applications, we encourage you to review their privacy policies and be careful about the information you submit or share.
What information do we collect?
Information You Provide – We and our service providers collect information that you provide when you use the Online Services, including, but not limited to, when you:
create an account;
make a donation;
contribute content to the Online Services, such as when you “Share Your Story” or comment on an article;
use interactive features on the Online Services, such as our tools and apps or the chat feature;
make a purchase (e.g., purchase products from the Austin Women’s Health Center Marketplace);
sign an online petition;
apply for a job or for a volunteer or internship opportunity;
sign up to receive updates and other communications from Austin Women’s Health Center;
enter a contest, sweepstakes, or promotion;
participate in polls or surveys; or
otherwise contact us with a question, comment, or request.
The information that you provide us can include, but is not limited to:
your name;
your photograph;
your contact information, such as your physical address, email address, and phone number;
your username, password, and other account information;
demographic information such as your age, gender, and ethnicity;
transaction-related information, such as credit card information;
information you provide when submitting an application for employment, internship, or volunteer opportunities; and
information you provide when you request information or contact us.
You have control over your own privacy. Think carefully before providing any personal or financial information online.
Information Automatically Collected From You – We and our service providers may automatically collect certain technical information from your computer or mobile device over time and across different websites when you use the Online Services, such as your Internet Protocol address, your geographic location, your browser type, your operating system, the pages you view on the Online Services, the pages you view immediately before and after you access the Online Services, and the search terms you enter on the Online Services. This information allows us and our service providers to recognize you and personalize your experience if you return to the Online Services, to improve the Online Services and the services we provide, and to provide you with Targeted Advertisements. We and our service providers may collect this information using “cookies,” which are small text files that many websites save on your computer when you visit and access when you return, or similar technologies. We also collect this information by setting a unique anonymous identifier called User ID, set by Universal Google Analytics. User ID helps identify unique users across multiple devices and browsers. Clearing your cookies does not ensure that you will not be recognized as the same unique visitor even after you cleared them. Website visitors who do not want their data collected with Google Analytics in this way can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on.
Online advertisements
Our third-party advertising partners may use cookies and similar technologies on the Online Services and on third-party websites on which our ads appear, which allow the advertising partners to track certain information about user behavior, such as “click-stream data.” The information practices of these advertising partners are governed by their own privacy policies and are not governed by this Privacy Policy.
Where is this information processed?
Information collected through the Online Services will be processed in and subject to the laws of the United States. In addition, we may transfer your information outside the United States to our affiliates and service providers located in other countries. By using the Online Services, you consent to such transfer to, and processing in, the United States and these other countries.
How is your information secured?
We strive to maintain reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to safeguard the information collected through the Online Services. However, no information system can be 100% secure, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information. Moreover, we are not responsible for the security of information you transmit to the Online Services over networks that we do not control, including the Internet and wireless networks. If you have concerns about the security of sensitive information, do not send it electronically.
Your choices
If you do not want the Online Services to collect information through the use of cookies, you can set your web browser to reject cookies from the Online Services. Each browser is different, so you should check your browser’s “Help” menu to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you reject or block cookies from the Online Services, however, the Online Services may not function as intended.
In addition to the records left on your computer by cookies, your browser and operating system contain other records of your web browsing and other actions (e.g., browser history). As with cookies, you can find information about how to clear these history trails in your browser’s “Help” menu.
We do not currently respond to web browser “do not track” signals. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Policy. For more information about do not track, visit www.allaboutdnt.org.
If you wish to review the contact information we have on file for you, correct your contact information, or inform us how you wish your contact information to be used, please contact our staff using the contact information below.
To opt-out of Google Analytics for the web, visit the Google Analytics opt-out page and install the add-on for your browser.
Changes to this Privacy Policy
If we update this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by posting a new Privacy Policy on this page. If we make any revisions that materially change the ways in which we use or disclose the information previously collected from you through the Online Services, we will give you the opportunity to consent to such changes before applying them to that information.
Contact us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or about our data practices regarding the information we collect through the Online Services, please contact us at:
Austin Women’s Health Center
1902 S. IH-35
Austin, TX 78704
questions@austinwomenshealth.com
512-443-9595
When you contact us or otherwise submit content via the Online Services, if you desire to remain anonymous, you should not tell us your name or the names of your friends or any other individuals. To fully protect your privacy, do not provide any information that you think may identify you or others.
This Privacy Policy was last updated on October 12, 2017.
